PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT MANAGER/NATIONAL SALES COORDINATOR

Summary

A highly organized and detail-oriented Executive Assistant with over 17 years' experience providing thorough and skillful administrative support to senior executives. Dedicated and focused; able to prioritize and complete multiple tasks and follow through to achieve project goals. An independent and self-motivated professional with excellent research and writing skills; able to grow positive relationships with clients and colleagues at all organizational levels. Experience working with Asian factories and suppliers. Ability to work with highly conceptual ideas and to usher them through to execution. Strong analytical skills. Ability to manage multiple projects simultaneously. Ability to adapt quickly to changing priorities and strategies, and a high tolerance for ambiguity. Leading and influencing across teams and departments without direct supervisory authority. Ability to travel.

Highlights

Windows 1995-2007 and XP, Microsoft Office applications (Outlook (Mail, Calendar, and Contacts), Word, Excel, Access, Power Point), PageMaker, Lotus 123, Timberline, RLA (HyperTerminal), GEN 60 Windows Client, Report, Business Card Scan, Remote Assistance, FedEx, Adonix, Facebook, Twitter, Flickr, Youtube, Miva, Internet Explorer, Firefox, Laser Optical, GS1, ERP, SAP, and Produmex. *Managing Skills, Ability to work well under pressure to meet tight deadlines, Product Development, Quality Control & Assurance, Receipt of Containers, Merchandising, Trade Shows, Product Displays, Market Research/Analysis, Attention to detail, Problem-solving, Data Analysis, Organization, Creative, and time management skills.

Accomplishments

Planned, directed, coordinated and assigned manpower to efficiently meet production requirements.

Experience

Product Development Manager/National Sales Coordinator

January 2007 to Current University Of Pennsylvania Health System il/4 Dayton, NJ

- Provide executive assistance to Chairman Managing multiple projects of varying product types and complexities while maintaining cost and
 schedule targets Working closely with overseas development, tooling, and manufacturing to ensure successful project completion Tracking
 the fabrication of premium samples for sales presentations, toy fairs, and photo shoots Exhibit strong knowledge and awareness of historical
 and competitive market place Product development liaison between executives, factories, sculptors and quality control department.
- Attend toy shows and schools to introduce and sell products.
- Work together with Patent lawyers to trademark and or register products Review and comment on all production approval samples and approve packaging artwork.
- Lead role in the collaborative process of brainstorming and defining new products.
- Manage and ensure implementation of new product development and sourcing.
- Ownership of product development plan and development calendar.
- Work closely with existing Asian suppliers and cultivate new supplier relationships to develop new and existing products.
- International and Domestic travel including China for product, catalog and marketing materials.
- Analyze competitive lines, category pricing, and research data.
- Selection of margin goals on assigned products & projects.
- Develops and manages project time lines & coordinates appropriate details.
- Manage the efforts of cross-functional team members in completing projects to create high-quality products.
- Monitor category performance to ensure sales volume and profit goals are met.
- Work hand in hand with the sales organization to prepare and deliver presentations to key customers as the product matter expert.
- Creation of item, UPC and GTIN numbers.

Assistant Controller/Accounting Clerk

December 2005 to March 2006 ASR LLC & ASR INTERIORS i1/4 City, STATE

- Provided administrative assistance to President, Controller, Accountant, company's employees and Fisher Island's residents.
- Resolved Human Resources and Payroll issues with office staff.
- Prepared purchase orders, posted pending invoices, job supplies inventory, check requests and cutting checks.
- Responsible for employee's, vendor's and subcontractor's files.
- Gathered Contracts, Bonds, Waiver and Release of Lien, W9/Tax Id, Proof of Company, Certificate of liability Insurance, Notice to Owner, Sworn Statements, and Payment Applications from Subcontractors for accounting and project management department.
- Updated Occupational & Municipal Contractors License.
- Tracked spreadsheets for owner of the company for miscellaneous/vendor expenses.

Senior Secretary

August 2000 to March 2002 REYNOLDS SMITH AND HILLS, INC i1/4 City, STATE

- Office Manger assistance to Vice President of Institutional Department, architects, and engineers in architectural/engineering firm
- Provided comprehensive executive secretarial and administrative assistance to Vice President.
- Prepared proposals for Aviation, Commercial and Institutional departments.
- Coordinated activities through 13 branch offices (HR, Accounting, Legal, MIS and Payroll departments).
- Prepared monthly invoices for all Subconsultants and open accounts.
- Performed reconciliations of petty cash and checking account.
- Printed weekly and monthly accounting/detailed reports for Vice President.

• Inputted employee timesheets weekly.

Referrals Clerk

May 1998 to March 1999 DR. FIELDS & GARCIA OFFICE i1/4 City, STATE

- Provided secretarial assistance to three General Doctors and Office Manager.
- Called insurance companies to receive authorizations for patient's referrals to specialists.
- Called in patient's prescriptions to local pharmacies.
- Returned patient's phone calls for doctors twice weekly.
- Front desk supervision, answering multiple phone lines, scheduling appointments and filing.

Medical Records Analyst/Scanner

July 1995 to May 1998 PALMETTO GENERAL HOSPITAL i1/4 City, STATE

- Provided clerical support to 700 doctors with medical records request.
- Provided semi-weekly assistance to chart signing meetings.
- Created a bi-weekly list of delinquent records.
- Sent out monthly suspension and warning letters to doctors.
- Organized and maintained a high quantity of medical records.
- Scanned medical records through laser optical into database.
- · Organized and maintained charts in numerical filing system.
- Gathered personal information from patients in maternity to complete newborn's birth certificates.

Education

High School Diploma HIALEAH-MIAMI LAKES SENIOR HIGH i1/4 City, State

Languages

I am fluent in both English and Spanish

Skills

Accounting, Accountant, administrative, photo, PageMaker, scheduling appointments, Attention to detail, basic, Bonds, bi, catalog, charts, clerical, competitive, Contracts, Controller, Client, Data Analysis, database, English, ERP, filing, functional, Human Resources, HR, Insurance, Internet Explorer, inventory, Laser, Legal, letters, Lotus 123, Managing, Market Research/Analysis, market, marketing materials, meetings, Merchandising, Access, Excel, Mail, Microsoft Office applications, Office, Outlook, Power Point, Windows, Word, MIS, new product development, Office Manager, operating systems, packaging, Payroll, presentations, pricing, Problem-solving, Product Development, profit, project management, proposals, quality, Quality Control, research, sales, SAP, secretarial, Spanish, spreadsheets, supervision, Tax, phone, Timberline, time management, Trade Shows